[MUSIC]
[موسيقى]
You've heard me hint about this a lot today, and
لقد سمعتني ألمح عن ذلك كثيرا اليوم،
the practical issues of stochastic gradient are pretty significant.
تعتبر الأمور العملية المتعلقة بالتدرج العشوائي ملحوظة بشكل كبير.
So for most of the remaining of the module,
وبالتالي، في أغلب ما تبقى من هذه الوحدة،
we'll talk about how to address some of those practical issues.
سنتحدث عن كيفية التعامل مع تلك الأمور العملية.
Let's take a moment to review the stochastic gradient algorithm.
لنراجع سريعًا خوارزمية التدرج العشوائي.
We initialize our parameters, our coefficients to some value,
نبدأ بإلحاق بعض القيم للمعاملات التي لدينا،
let's say all 0.
ولنفترض بأنها جميعًا 0.
And then until convergence, we go 1 data point at a time, and 1 feature at a time.
وقبل الوصول إلى عملية التحويل، نتعامل مع كل نقطة بيانات وكل ميزة من الميزات بشكل منفرد.
And we update the coefficient of that feature by just computing the gradient
ثم نقوم بتحديث معامل تلك الميزة فقط من خلال حساب التدرج
at that single data point.
عند تلك النقطة.
So I need a contribution of each data point 1 at a time.
لأنني أريد كل نقطة أن تساهم بشكل منفرد في تلك العملية.
So we're scaling down the data, update the parameters 1 data point at a time.
سنقوم بتقليل حجم البيانات، ثم تحديث المتغيرات كل على حدى.
For example, I see my first data point here 0 awesome, 2 awful, sentiment -1.
مثلًا، ألاحظ أن أول نقطة بيانات تحتوي على 0 "جيد"، و 2 "سيئ"، والحالة العاطفية -1.
I make an update which pushes me towards predicting -1 to this data point.
ثم أقوم بعمل التحديثات التي تصل بي إلى التوقع -1 لتلك النقطة.
Now if the next data point is also negative,
وإذا كانت النقطة التالية أيضًا سالبة،
I'm going to make another kind of negative push.
سأقوم بعمل تحديث آخر سلبي.
If the third one is negative, make another negative push, and so on.
وإذا كانت النقطة الثالثة سالبة، فسأقوم بعمل تحديث سلبي آخر، وهكذا.
And so, one worry, one bad thing that can happen with stochastic
من الأشياء السيئة التي قد تحدث عند التعامل مع التدرج العشوائي
gradient is if your data is implicitly sorted in a certain way.
هي إذا كانت البيانات مخزنة بطريقة خفية نوعًا ما.
So, for example,
إذن، على سبيل المثال،
all the negative data points are coming before all the positives.
حينما تأتي جميع نقاط البيانات السالبة قبل مثيلتها الموجبة.
They can introduce some bad behaviors to the algorithm, bad practical performance.
فقد تحدث بعض السلوكيات الغير متوقعة في الخوارزمية، مما ينذر بأداء عملي غير مناسب.
And so we worry about this a lot and it's really significant.
لذا أنا أنصحك بالتعامل بحذر مع تلك الأمور، فهي مؤثرة للغاية.
So, because of that, before you start running stochastic gradient you
وبسبب كل ذلك، قبل أن تقوم بعمل التدرج العشوائي
should always shuffle the rows of the data, mix them up.
يجب دائمًا خلط صفوف البيانات.
So that you don't have this long regions of, say,
حتى لا يكون هناك مناطق كبيرة من البيانات
negatives before positives, or young people before older people.
السلبية منها قبل الإيجابية، أو مثلًا الشباب قبل كبار السن.
Or people who live in one country versus people who live in another country.
أو سكان دولة معينة قبل سكان دولة أخرى.
You want to mix it all up.
يجب دائمًا التأكد من خلط البيانات.
So what that means, from the context of the stochastic gradient algorithm that we
إذن ففي سياق خوارزمية التدرج العشوائي التي رأيناها
just saw, is just adding a line at the beginning where you shuffle the data.
سوف نضيف سطرًا في مقدمة الخوارزمية يوضح خلط البيانات.
So before doing anything, you should start by shuffling the data.
من المهم جدًا ألا تنسى خلط البيانات قبل البدء.